Eastern Nursing Research Society Records 2000.0141
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Eastern Nursing Research Society Records
1986-2006
2000.0141
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
17.0 Linear feet
The Eastern Nursing Research Society (ENRS) is comprised of RNs and others interested in nursing research. It was established in 1988 as the research arm of the Mid-Atlantic Regional Nursing Association (MARNA) and the New England Organization for Nursing (NEON). The ENRS region includes Connecticut, Delaware, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Vermont and Washington, D.C.
Eastern Nursing Research Society
History
The Eastern Nursing Research Society (ENRS) is comprised of RNs and others interested in nursing research. It was established in 1988 as the research arm of the Mid-Atlantic Regional Nursing Association ( MARNA) and the New England Organization for Nursing ( NEON). The purpose of the ENRS is to create a community for nurses interested in research in the Eastern region of the United States. The ENRS region includes Connecticut, Delaware, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Vermont and Washington, D.C.
The presidents of the organization have been:
Lillie M. Shortridge, 1988-1989
Veronica Rempusheski, 1989-1990
Keville Frederickson, 1990-1991
Gail Harkness, 1991-1992
Jean R. Miller, 1992-1994
Kathryn S. Hegedus, 1994-1996
Cheryl B. Stetler, 1996-1998
Ann L. O'Sullivan, 1998-2000
Terry T. Fulmer, 2000-2002
Suzanne C. Smeltzer, 2002-2004
Dorothy Jones, 2004-2006
Mary Sullivan, 2006-2008
Judith Erlen, 2008-2010
Scope and Content
The collection contains agendas, minutes, correspondence, membership materials and other administrative records of the organization. It appears that these materials were maintained by several individuals in several discrete files. This arrangement has been retained and so the dates in the administrative series overlap to some extent but the folders have been psted alphabetically in the finding aid for ease of use. The organization also has an annual conference with pubpshed proceedings, which are also included in the collection. The proceedings are arranged chronologically.
Arrangement
Series I: Administrative Files (undated, 1986-1996) includes agendas, minutes of meetings, correspondence, printouts of electronic mail, membership materials, ballots, agreements and some financial materials.
Series II: Conference Files (undated, 1988-2006) contains the proceedings of the conferences as well as records concerning the planning and running of the conference for some years. Administrative files for the conferences are filed after the proceedings for each year. Mounted posters of the proceedings for the first ten conferences are located in Box 4.
Series III: President's Files (undated, 1992-1998) contains the files specifically associated with, created and transferred by the President of the organization.
Series IV: Photographs (1993, 1998, 2002) contains color snapshots of the conferences.
Box inventories of subsequent additions are included at the end of the Series' listings.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to nursing history and education, see especially the records of the North East Organization for Nursing ( NEON). For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The ENRS Records were donated by the organization in October 2000 and June 2002. New materials are added regularly.
Mid-Atlantic Regional Nursing Association.; New England Organization for Nursing.; Administrative Records.; Advertisements.; Bylaws.; Correspondence.; Financial Records.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Minutes.; Newsletters.; Notes.; Nurses--Societies, etc.; Nursing--New England.; Nursing--Research.; Photocopies.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Professional organization.; Publications.
- Series I: Administrative Files, undated, 1986-1998
  - Addresses and telephone numbers, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Administrative files, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Administrative files, 1988-1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Administrative files, 1986-1990 (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - Administrative files, 1986-1993 (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Administrative files, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Administrative files, 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - American Nurse's Foundation, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Annual Research Conference, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Awards, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - Awards, 1994-1997 (Box 8, Folder 135)
  - Awards Committee annual reports, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Ballots, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Ballots, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Ballots, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Board activities, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Board meetings, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Board meetings, 1991-1996 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Board meetings, 1993-1996 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Board membership and communication, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Board Minutes, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board minutes, correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Budget, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Business meeting, 1993-1996 (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - By-Laws, undated, 1992-1995 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - By-Laws, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 134)
  - Conference business, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Conference calls, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Conference calls to board members, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Conferences and financial report, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Executive Board meetings, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Executive Board and communications, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Friends of the National Institute of Nursing Research, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 142)
  - General business, 1989-2003 (Box 13)
  - General business, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - General business, 1993-2000 (Box 12)
  - General business (incl. Conference history), 1996-2001 (Box 11)
  - General business, 1999-2000 (Box 10)
  - Guidelines, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Handbook for officers and chairpersons, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 174)
  - Historical data, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Historical description and publicity, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Interest groups, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - MARNA agendas, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Member posts, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Members research interest, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - Membership business meetings, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Membership and Nominating committee, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Membership directory
    - 1993 (Box 8, Folder 133)
    - 1995 (Box 10)
    - 1997 (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - 1998 (Box 8, Folder 144)
    - 2000 (Box 8, Folder 145)
  - Membership Mailings, NEON Bylaws, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Membership meetings and posts, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1992-1998 (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Minutes, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - NEON, 1987-1997 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Newsletters, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Newsletters, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Newsletters, 1994-1999 (Box 8, Folder 147)
  - Nominating committee, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Nominations, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - Postconference and general business, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Program Planning Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Puetz & Associates, Inc., 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 141)
  - Regional, national, international research groups, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Research Nursing and Health Agreement, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Shortridge Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sigma Theta Tau
    - undated (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - 1997 (Box 8, Folder 140)
  - Steering Committee correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer's report/Budget, 1994-1998 (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Steering Committee members and meetings, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Updates, undated (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - Visions and goals, undated (Box 6, Folder 116)
- Series II: Conference Files, undated, 1988-2006
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - MARNA Conference, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Conference files, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Conference files, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Program, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 175)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Program, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 176)
  - Program materials, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Conference planning, 1992-1999 (Box 8, Folder 131)
    - Conference report, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Program, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 177)
  - Annual programs, 1993-1996 (Box 7, Folder 124)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 1993-1995 (Box 7, Folder 125)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Abstract reviews (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Advertisement/publicity (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Agenda: planning and minutes (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Budget (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Consultation: Topic and Schedules (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Conference planning and background (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Contact hours (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Hotel contract (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Interest groups outcomes and references (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Paper presentation abstracts (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Poster presentation abstracts (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Pre-session presentations (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 178)
    - Program compilation (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Research information exchange (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Registration procedure (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Scientific sessions (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Tour options and travel agency (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence, 1994-2000 (Box 8, Folder 146)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, Binghamton, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 126)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Agendas and planning minutes (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Brochures, participant's certificates (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Conference abstract reviews (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Conference correspondence (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Letter to Panetti, notecards for paper presentation (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Paper presentation posts (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Proceedings abstracts
      - Pregnancy and postpartum issues (Box 2, Folder 73)
      - Parenting: childcare and development (Box 2, Folder 74)
      - Issues related to caregiving (Box 2, Folder 75)
      - Psychosocial issues in illness (Box 2, Folder 76)
      - Attitudes and coping with AIDS (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Proceedings abstracts
      - Mechanical ventilation (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - Health issues related to gender and age (Box 2, Folder 79)
      - Instrumentation (Box 2, Folder 80)
      - Clinical practice innovations (Box 2, Folder 81)
      - Ethics (Box 2, Folder 82)
      - Community health issues (Box 2, Folder 83)
      - Symposium A (Box 2, Folder 84)
      - Symposium B (Box 2, Folder 85)
      - Symposium C (Box 2, Folder 86)
      - Issues on the elderly (Box 2, Folder 87)
      - Cancer issues (Box 2, Folder 88)
      - Women's issues (Box 2, Folder 89)
      - Nurse and Nursing issues (Box 2, Folder 90)
      - All other papers (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Paper presentation and post (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Poster correspondence (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Poster presentation--Yes (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Poster presentation--No (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Pre-session correspondence (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Conference materials (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Planning committee, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 179)
    - Special interest group, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 138)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 1996
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 180)
  - Mounted conference posters, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 1999
    - Files (Box 10)
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 181)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 2000
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 182)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 2001
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 184)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 2002
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 183)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 2003
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 185)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 2004
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 186)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 2005
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 187)
  - Eastern Nursing Research Conference, 2006
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 188)
  - National Nursing Research Roundtable
    - 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - 1993-1996 (Box 7, Folder 128)
    - 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 143)
- Series III: President's files, undated, 1991-1998
  - Candidate elections, 1991-1997 (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Subseries A: President Rempusheski, undated
    - Email, undated (Box 8, Folder 148)
  - Subseries B: President Stetler, 1996-1998
    - Email
      - 1996 (Box 8, Folder 149)
      - 1997 January (Box 8, Folder 150)
      - 1997 February (Box 8, Folder 151)
      - 1997 March (Box 8, Folder 152)
      - 1997 April (Box 8, Folder 153)
      - 1997 May (Box 8, Folder 154)
      - 1997 June (Box 8, Folder 155)
      - 1997 July (Box 8, Folder 156)
      - 1997 August (Box 8, Folder 157)
      - 1997 September (Box 8, Folder 158)
      - 1997 October (Box 8, Folder 159)
      - 1997 November (Box 8, Folder 160)
      - 1997 December (Box 8, Folder 161)
      - 1998 January (Box 8, Folder 162)
      - 1998 February (Box 8, Folder 163)
      - 1998 March (Box 8, Folder 164)
      - 1998 April (Box 9, Folder 165)
      - 1998 May (Box 9, Folder 166)
      - 1998 June (Box 9, Folder 167)
      - 1998 July (Box 9, Folder 168)
      - 1998 August (Box 9, Folder 169)
      - 1998 December (Box 9, Folder 170)
      - 1999 (Box 9, Folder 171)
    - Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 173)
    - Research utilization: Stetler/Grady model, undated (Box 9, Folder 172)
- Series IV: Photographs, 1993, 1998-2002
  - Boston conference, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Rochester conference, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Penn State conference, 2002 (Box 11)
- Series V: 2009 addition, undated, 1995-2009
  - 4th Annual Leadership Conference, 2004 (Box 14)
    - 17th Annual Conference--Scientific Sessions, 2005 April 7 - 9
    - 18th Annual Conference--Scientific Sessions, 2006 April 20 - 22
    - 19th Annual Conference, 2007 April 12 - 14
    - 19th Annual Conference--Scientific Sessions, 2007 April 12 - 14
    - 20th Annual Conference--Scientific Sessions, 2008 March 27 - 29
    - 21st Annual Conference--Program, 2009 March 19 - 21
    - 21st Annual Conference--Scientific Sessions, 2009 March 19 - 21
    - 21st Annual Conference--Proceedings (2 folders), 2009 March 19 - 21
    - American Nurses Foundation, 2005
    - Board of Directors, 2004 (Box 15)
    - Board of Directors, 2005
    - Board of Directors, 2006
    - Board of Directors, 2007
    - Board of Directors, 2008
    - By-Laws, 2005
    - Chair-- Mary Sullivan
      - Agenda, 2006 August 16
      - Notes (2 folders), 2005
    - Conference Planning, 2006
    - Council for the Advancement of Nursing Science, 2005
    - Council for the Advancement of Nursing Science, 2006
    - Council for the Advancement of Nursing Science, 2007
    - ENRS 20th Anniversary, 2008 March 2
    - Evaluations, 2005
    - Handbook for Officers and Chairpersons, undated
    - Membership, 2004
    - National State of the Science Congress in Nursing Research, 2006 October 12 - 14
    - National Nursing Research Roundtable, 2005
    - National Nursing Research Roundtable, 2007 March 1 - 2
    - Reports
      - 2004
      - 2006
      - 2007
    - Mary Sullivan records
      - Board of Directors, 1995-1996
      - Board of Directors (2 folders), 1997
      - Board of Directors, 1998
      - Board of Directors, 1999
      - Board of Directors, 2000
      - Board of Directors, 2001
      - Board of Directors, 2002
      - National Nursing Research Roundtable, 2000
      - Secretary's records, 1998-2000
- Series VI: 2012 addition, 2011
  - Conferences, 2011 (Box 16)